Guide to the John Gerassi Oral History Collection ALBA.AUDIO.018
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
John Gerassi Oral History Collection
1980
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Gerassi, John
ALBA.AUDIO.018
1.5 Linear Feet in audio cabinet and 2 cassette boxes
89 audiocassettes
104 sound discs (cd)
Journalist and scholar John ("Tito") Gerassi received his MA at Columbia University and earned his doctorate at the London School of Economics. Among his publications are The Great Fear in Latin America (1965), The Boys of Boise (1966), and the biography Jean-Paul Sartre: Hated Conscience of His Century, (1989). The Premature Anti-Fascists: Oral History of American and Canadian Volunteers in the Spanish Civil War was published in 1986, and is a tribute to the men and women who volunteered to fight on behalf of the Spanish Republic. This collection contains 227 audiocassettes consisting of 89 separate interviews with individual veterans that were conducted for Gerassi's project.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers.
Arrangement
Each audiocassette has been assigned a unique item number (e.g. ALBA A 18-001), and the collection is arranged in item number order. The item number order follows the alphabetical order of the last name of the interviewee. A small number of tapes with Gerassi's research notes have been placed at the end of the collection.
The files are grouped into one series:
Missing Title
I, Oral History Tapes
Historical/Biographical Note
Journalist and scholar John ("Tito") Gerassi was born in France in July 1931, to Fernando Gerassi, a Turkish-born artist of Sephardic Jewish heritage, and Ukranian born Stepha Awdykowicz. Moving between Barcelona and Paris, the couple belonged to the cosmopolitan circle of artists and intellectuals who congregated in cafes to argue art and politics, and counted Jean-Paul Sartre and Simone de Beauvoir as close friends. When civil war broke out in Spain in 1936, Fernando Gerassi joined the Loyalist forces. He served as a general in the Spanish Army and became the inspiration for the figure of Gomez, the artist and revolutionary in Sartre's trilogy Roads to Freedom. Following the Fascist victory in Spain, the Gerassi family emigrated to the United States in 1940. John Gerassi was raised in New York City and attended Columbia University. He spent a decade in journalism, worked as an editor for Time and, later, Newsweek before serving as a foreign correspondent for the New York Times. He left journalism to pursue a career in academia and earned his doctorate at the London School of Economics. He was as an instructor at the John Kennedy Freedom School in Berlin and at the University of California at Irvine before joining the faculty of Queens College of the City University of New York in 1978. Among his publications are The Great Fear in Latin America (1965); The Boys of Boise (1966); the biography Jean-Paul Sartre: Hated Conscience of His Century, (1989); and "The Comintern, the Fronts and the CPUSA," in New Studies in the Politics and Culture of U.S. Communism, (1993).
His father's death in 1974 and his own subsequent journey to Barcelona the following year kindled his interest in the Spanish Civil War and the men and woman who volunteered to fight on behalf of the Republic. The Premature Anti-Fascists: Oral History of American and Canadian Volunteers in the Spanish Civil War, Gerassi's tribute to these volunteers, was published in 1986. In the preface to that work, he describes his methodology for selecting and recording the oral histories that became the foundation for his study. In the spring of 1979, Gerassi sent out one-page questionnaires to 300 U.S. and Canadian veterans of the Spanish Civil War: From the 210 answers, I selected 50 absolute 'musts' to be personally interviewed. By making another 100 phone calls, I chose another 30. And 50 more were picked along the way, either by Mr. Ray Villis, my principal interviewer, or by myself and Ms. Chantal Ferraro, my main researcher...Of the 130 interviewed, 65 were fully transcribed; the rest were used for background verification. The resulting 18,000 pages were then edited down by me...Rather than fill scores of pages with tridots, brackets, and explanatory footnotes, I took the liberty of editing the interviews so that each section could read smoothly as a narrative.
Although the study is a sympathetic and admiring portrait of the veterans as a group, and Gerassi took pains to remain true to the intent and voice of the individual accounts, some of the veterans were displeased with Gerassi's polished edits of their oral histories.
Provenance
These oral history tapes were separated from the John Gerassi Collection, which was donated to Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives in three separate accessions. The bulk of the material was donated by John Gerassi in 1983. Subsequent donations were made by Betsy Gimbel in 1988 and by Ray Villis in 1997. This collection came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of ALBA collections, formerly housed at Brandeis University.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Researchers interested in using audiovisual materials in this collection (films, cassette tapes, VHS tapes, et cetera) must use a digitized copy, which we refer to as an access copy. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room; materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
John Gerassi Papers, ALBA #18.
ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains 227 audiocassettes consisting of 89 separate interviews with individual veterans. The average taping session was 7 hours and there are multiple tapes associated with most of the interviews. The interviews cover the following topics: family background and political affiliations, their motivations for joining the International Brigades, experiences and impressions of Spain, instances of discrimination and harassment during WWII and subsequently during the McCarthy era. Although most of the oral history interviews were conducted with combat veterans, there are also several interviews with women who, like Salaria Kee (aka Kea) O'Reilly, Nan Green, and Rose Wachsman Sorkin, served in the Medical Service or, in the case of Evelyn Hutchins, as a driver.
The collection also includes three tapes with spoken research notes that Gerassi recorded during his visits to libraries and archives at Brandeis University, Cleveland University, and the Toronto Public Library, as well as a tape of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) 43rd Anniversary event honoring African-American volunteers. An additional tape documents Gerassi's contract with Ray Villis, his principal interviewer on the project.
Note to Researchers: Transcripts of many of the tapes in this ocllection can be found in the John Gerassi Papers (ALBA 018).
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Biography; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Women.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Personal narratives.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Hospitals.; Audiocassettes.; Oral history.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- African Americans; Fishman, Mosess (Moe), 1916-2007; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Brigada Internacional, XV; Kea, Salaria (O'Reilly); Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Abraham Lincoln Battalion; Weissman, Irving, 1913-1998; Bessie, Alvah Cecil, 1904-1985; Hutchins, Evelyn, 1910-1982; Lending, Edward Isaac, 1912-2003; Kilpatrick, Admiral; Bailey, Bill, 1911-1995; Hunter, Oscar; Harris, Sydney, 1916-; Pistone, Rosario.; Ornitz, Lou, 1912-1984; Marzani, Carl; Lossowski, Vincent, 1914-1984; Nelson, Steve, 1903-1993; Murra, John V.; Rosenstein, Herman, 1915-; Green, Nan; Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy; Goff, Irving; Wolff, Milton.; Gladnick, Robert; Watt, George, 1913-1994; Villis, Ray; Steck, Robert; Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion; Stamm, Morris; Scheutrum, Walter; Dent, Walter; Colodny, Robert Garland.; Brown, Archie, 1911-1990.; Ferraro, Chantal; Geiser, Carl; Gates, John, 1913-1992; Felsen, Milt, 1912-2005
- Series I: Oral History Interviews
  - Amesbury, Clifton, 1980; cuid9045 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_001)
  - Amesbury, Clifton, 1980; cuid9046 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_002)
  - Bailey, Bill, 1980; cuid9047 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-003 A-B, Box 3, Audiocassette 18_003)
  - Bailey, Bill, 1980; cuid9048 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-004 A-B, Box 3, Audiocassette 18_003)
  - Bailey, Bill, 1980; cuid9049 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-005 A-B, Box 3, Audiocassette 18_005)
  - Bailey, Bill, 1980; cuid9050 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-006 A-B, Box 3, Audiocassette 18_006)
  - Bailey, Bill, 1980; cuid9051 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-007 A-B, Box 3, Audiocassette 18_007)
  - Bender, Edward, 1980; cuid9052 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_008)
  - Bender, Edward, 1980; cuid9053 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_009)
  - Bender, Edward, 1980; cuid9054 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_010)
  - Bender, Edward, 1980; cuid9055 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_011)
  - Bender, Edward, 1980; cuid9056 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_012)
  - Bender, Edward, 1980; cuid9057 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_013)
  - Bender, Edward, 1980; cuid9058 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_014)
  - Bender, Edward, 1980; cuid9059 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_015)
  - Bender, Edward, 1980; cuid9060 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_016)
  - Bender, Edward, 1980; cuid9061 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_017)
  - Bender, Edward, 1980; cuid9062 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_018)
  - Bender, Edward, 1980; cuid9063 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_019)
  - Benet, James, 1980; cuid9064 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_020)
  - Benet, James, 1980; cuid9065 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_021)
  - Bessie, Alvah, 1980; cuid9066 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-022 A-B, Box 3, Audiocassette 18_022)
  - Bessie, Alvah, 1980; cuid9067 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-023 A-B, Box 3, Audiocassette 18_023)
  - Bierman, Sam, 1980; cuid9068 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_024)
  - Bierman, Sam, 1980; cuid9069 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_025)
  - Bonetti, Frank, 1980; cuid9070 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-026 A-B, Box 3, Audiocassette 18_026)
  - Bonetti, Frank, 1980; cuid9071 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-027 A-B, Box 3, Audiocassette 18_027)
  - Bonetti, Frank, 1980; cuid9072 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-028 A-B, Box 3, Audiocassette 18_028)
  - Bortz, Lou, 1980; cuid9073 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_029)
  - Brandeis: Notes on, 1980; cuid9074 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_030)
  - Brennan, William, 1980; cuid9075 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_031)
  - Brennan, William, 1980; cuid9076 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_032)
  - Brown, Archie, 1980; cuid9077 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_033)
  - Brown, Archie, 1980; cuid9078 (Box 3, Audiocassette 18_034)
  - Brown, Archie, 1980; cuid9079 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_035)
  - Cohen, Milt, 1980; cuid9080 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_036)
  - Colodny, Robert, 1980; cuid9081 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_037)
  - Colodny, Robert, 1980; cuid9082 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_038)
  - Colodny, Robert, 1980; cuid9083 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_039)
  - Colodny, Robert, 1980; cuid9084 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_040)
  - Colow, Maury, 1980; cuid9085 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_041)
  - Colow, Murray, 1980; cuid9086 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_042)
  - Colow, Murray, 1980; cuid9087 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_043)
  - Dent, Walter, 1980; cuid9088 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_044)
  - Dent, Walter, 1980; cuid9089 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_045)
  - Dent, Walter, 1980; cuid9090 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_046)
  - Edwards, Lionel, 1980; cuid9091 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_047)
  - Edwards, Lionel, 1980; cuid9092 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_048)
  - Fasanella, Ralph, 1980; cuid9093 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_049)
  - Fasanella, Ralph, 1980; cuid9094 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_050)
  - Fasanella, Ralph, 1980; cuid9095 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_051)
  - Felsen, Milt, 1980; cuid9096 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_052)
  - Felsen, Milt, 1980; cuid9097 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_053)
  - Felsen, Milt, 1980; cuid9098 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_054)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1980; cuid9099 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_055)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1980; cuid9100 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_056)
  - Forbes, Alex, 1980; cuid9101 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_057)
  - Forbes, Alex, 1980; cuid9102 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_058)
  - Forester, Clarence, 1980; cuid9103 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_059)
  - Gates, John, 1980; cuid9104 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_060)
  - Gates, John, 1980; cuid9105 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_061)
  - Geiser, Carl, 1980; cuid9106 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_062)
  - Geiser, Carl, 1980; cuid9107 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_063)
  - Geiser, Carl, 1980; cuid9108 (Box 4, Audiocassette 18_064)
  - Gladnick, Robert, 1980; cuid9109 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-065 A-B, Box 4, Audiocassette 18_065)
  - Gladnick, Robert, 1980; cuid9110 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-066 C-D, Box 4, Audiocassette 18_066)
  - Gladnick, Robert, 1980; cuid9111 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-067 E-F, Box 4, Audiocassette 18_067)
  - Gladnick, Robert, 1980; cuid9112 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-068 G-H, Box 4, Audiocassette 18_068)
  - Gladnick, Robert, 1980; cuid9113 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-069 I-J, Box 5, Audiocassette 18_069)
  - Gladnick, Robert, 1980; cuid9114 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-070 K-L, Box 5, Audiocassette 18_070)
  - Gladnick, Robert, 1980; cuid9115 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-071 M-N, Box 5, Audiocassette 18_071)
  - Goff, Irving, 1980; cuid9116 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-072 A-B, Box 5, Audiocassette 18_072)
  - Goff, Irving, 1980; cuid9117 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-073 A-B, Box 5, Audiocassette 18_073)
  - Goff, Irving, 1980; cuid241 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-074 A-B, Box 5, Audiocassette 18_074)
  - Goff, Irving, 1980; cuid9118 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-075 A-B, Box 5, Audiocassette 18_075)
  - Goff, Irving, 1980; cuid9119 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-076 A, Box 5, Audiocassette 18_076)
  - Gold, Irving and Shirley, 1980; cuid9120 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_077)
  - Green, Nan, 1980; cuid9121 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_078)
  - Grodin, Danny, 1980; cuid9122 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_079)
  - Grodin, Danny; Thomas Lloyd, 1980; cuid9123 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_080)
  - Hall, Charles, 1980; cuid9124 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_081)
  - Hall, Charles, 1980; cuid9125 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_082)
  - Halonen, Oiva, 1980; cuid9126 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-083 A-B, Box 5, Audiocassette 18_083)
  - Halonen, Oiva, 1980; cuid9127 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-084, Box 5, Audiocassette 18_084)
  - Harris, Syd, 1980; cuid9128 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_085)
  - Harris, Syd, 1980; cuid9129 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_086)
  - Hinman, Luke, 1980; cuid9130 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_087)
  - Hinman, Luke, 1980; cuid9131 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_088)
  - Hunter, Oscar, 1980; cuid9132 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_089)
  - Hunter, Oscar, 1980; cuid9133 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_090)
  - Hutchins, Evelyn, 1980; cuid9134 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-091 A-B, Box 5, Audiocassette 18_091)
  - Hutchins, Evelyn, 1980; cuid242 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-092 A-B, Box 5, Audiocassette 18_092)
  - Johnson, Johnny, 1980; cuid9135 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_093)
  - Johnson, Johnny, 1980; cuid9136 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_094)
  - Kailin, Clarence, 1980; cuid9137 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_095)
  - Kailin, Clarence, 1980; cuid9138 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_096)
  - Kilpatrick, Admiral, 1980; cuid9139 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_097)
  - Kilpatrick, Admiral, 1980; cuid9140 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_098)
  - Kilpatrick, Admiral, 1980; cuid9141 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_099)
  - Kish, Leslie, 1980; cuid9142 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_100)
  - Kostoff, George, 1980; cuid9143 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_101)
  - Lamb, Leonard, 1980; cuid9144 (Box 5, Audiocassette 18_102)
  - Landis, Art, 1980; cuid9145 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_103)
  - Landis, Art, 1980; cuid9146 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_104)
  - Levenson, Leonard, 1980; cuid9147 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_105)
  - Levenson, Leonard, 1980; cuid9148 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_106)
  - Liversedge, Ron, 1980; cuid9149 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-107, Box 6, Audiocassette 18_107)
  - Liversedge, Ron, 1980; cuid9150 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-108, Box 6, Audiocassette 18_108)
  - Lloyd, Tommy, 1980; cuid9151 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_109)
  - Lossowski, Vincent, 1980; cuid9152 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_110)
  - Lossowski, Vincent, 1980; cuid9153 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_111)
  - Lossowski, Vincent, 1980; cuid9154 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_112)
  - Lossowski, Vincent; Ed Lending; Dave Miller, 1980; cuid9155 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_113)
  - Lossowski, Vincent; Ed Lending; Dave Miller, 1980; cuid9156 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_114)
  - Lossowski, Vincent; Ed Lending; Dave Miller, 1980; cuid9157 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_115)
  - Lossowski, Vincent; Ed Lending; Dave Miller, 1980; cuid9158 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_116)
  - Lossowski, Vincent; Ed Lending; Dave Miller, 1980; cuid9159 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_117)
  - Lossowski, Vincent; Ed Lending; Dave Miller, 1980; cuid9160 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_118)
  - Lossowski, Vincent; Ed Lending; Dave Miller, 1980; cuid9161 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_119)
  - Love, Vaughn, 1980; cuid9162 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-120 A-B, Box 6, Audiocassette 18_120)
  - Love, Vaughn, 1980; cuid9163 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-121 A-B, Box 6, Audiocassette 18_121)
  - Love, Vaughn, 1980; cuid9164 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-122 A-B, Box 6, Audiocassette 18_122)
  - Love, Vaughn, 1980; cuid9165 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-123 A-B, Box 6, Audiocassette 18_123)
  - Macleod, Don, 1980; cuid9166 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_124)
  - Maki, Martin, 1980; cuid9167 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_125)
  - Maki, Martin, 1980; cuid9168 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_126)
  - Maki, Martin, 1980; cuid9169 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_127)
  - Markert, Clement L., 1980; cuid9170 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_128)
  - Markert, Clement L., 1980; cuid9171 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_129)
  - Markert, Clement L., 1980; cuid9172 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_130)
  - Marzani, Carl, 1980; cuid9173 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_131)
  - Marzani, Carl, 1980; cuid9174 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_132)
  - Marzani, Carl, 1980; cuid9175 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_133)
  - Marzani, Carl, 1980; cuid9176 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_134)
  - Marzani, Carl, 1980; cuid9177 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_135)
  - Mattersdorfer, Fred, 1980; cuid9178 (Box 6, Audiocassette 18_136)
  - Mattersdorfer, Fred, 1980; cuid9179 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_137)
  - McDaniel, Luciel, 1980; cuid9180 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_138)
  - McDaniel, Luciel, 1980; cuid9181 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_139)
  - McElligott, John P., 1980; 2018; cuid9182 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_140)
  - McElligott, John P., 1980; 2018; cuid9183 (E-records tamwag_alba_audio018, E-records cuid9183, Box 7, Audiocassette 18_141)
  - Murra, John, 1980; cuid9184 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_142)
  - Murra, John, 1980; cuid9185 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_143)
  - Nelson, Steve, 1980; cuid9186 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-144 A-B, Box 7, Audiocassette 18_144)
  - Nelson, Steve, 1980; cuid9187 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-145 A-B, Box 7, Audiocassette 18_145)
  - Nelson, Steve, 1980; cuid9188 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-146 A-B, Box 7, Audiocassette 18_146)
  - Nelson, Steve, 1980; cuid9189 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-147, Box 7, Audiocassette 18_147)
  - Noble, Harry, 1980; cuid9190 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_148)
  - Norris, Len, 1980; cuid9191 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_149)
  - Norris, Len, 1980; cuid9192 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_150)
  - Norris, Len, 1980; cuid9193 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_151)
  - O'Reilly, Salaria Kee (a.k.a. Salaria Kea), 1980; cuid9194 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-152 A-B, Box 7, Audiocassette 18_152)
  - O'Reilly, Salaria Kee (a.k.a. Salaria Kea), 1980; cuid9195 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-153 A-B, Box 7, Audiocassette 18_153)
  - Ornitz, Louis, 1980; cuid9196 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_154)
  - Ornitz, Louis, 1980; cuid9197 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_155)
  - Osheroff, Abraham, 1980; cuid9198 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-156 A-B, Box 7, Audiocassette 18_156)
  - Osheroff, Abraham, 1980; cuid9199 (Box 1, Cd ALBA A 18-157 A-B, Box 7, Audiocassette 18_157)
  - Paivio, Jules, 1980; cuid9200 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_158)
  - Penrod, John and Jane, 1980; cuid9201 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_159)
  - Pistone, Rosario, 1980; cuid9202 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_160)
  - Pistone, Rosario, 1980; cuid9203 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_161)
  - Prago, Albert, 1980; cuid9204 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_162)
  - Prago, Albert, 1980; cuid9205 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_163)
  - Reed, Robert, 1980; cuid9206 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_164)
  - Reed, Robert, 1980; cuid9207 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_165)
  - Rintz, Norman, 1980; cuid9208 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_166)
  - Rosenstein, Herman, 1980; cuid9209 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_167)
  - Rosenstein, Herman, 1980; cuid9210 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_168)
  - Rosenstein, Herman, 1980; cuid9211 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_169)
  - Rossen, John, 1980; cuid9212 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18_170)
  - Rossen, John, 1980; cuid9213 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_171)
  - Russell, Ross, 1980; cuid9214 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_172)
  - Russell, Ross, 1980; cuid9215 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_173)
  - Schmidt, Norman James, 1980; cuid9216 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_174)
  - Schuetrum, Walter, 1980; cuid9217 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_175)
  - Schuetrum, Walter, 1980; cuid9218 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_176)
  - Schuetrum, Walter, 1980; cuid9219 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_177)
  - Sennett, William, 1980; cuid9220 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_178)
  - Sennett, William, 1980; cuid9221 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_179)
  - Service, Elman Rogers, 1980; 2018; cuid9222 (E-records tamwag_alba_audio018, E-records cuid9222, Box 8, Audiocassette 18_180)
  - Service, Elman Rogers, 1980; 2018; cuid9223 (E-records tamwag_alba_audio018, E-records cuid9223, Box 8, Audiocassette 18_181)
  - Shansky, Michael, 1980; cuid9224 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_182)
  - Shansky, Michael, 1980; cuid9225 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_183)
  - Skolnick, Abe, 1980; cuid9226 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_184)
  - Slater, Carl Theodore, 1980; cuid9227 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_185)
  - Sorenson, Henning, 1980; cuid9228 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_186)
  - Sorkin, Rose Wachsman, 1980; cuid9229 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_187)
  - Stamm, Morris, 1980; cuid9230 (Box 2, Cd ALBA A 18-188 A-B, Box 8, Audiocassette 18_188)
  - Stamm, Morris, 1980; cuid9231 (Box 2, Cd ALBA A 18-189 A-B, Box 8, Audiocassette 18_189)
  - Stamm, Morris, 1980; cuid9232 (Box 2, Cd ALBA A 18-190 A-B, Box 8, Audiocassette 18_190)
  - Stamm, Morris, 1980; cuid9233 (Box 2, Cd ALBA A 18-191 A-B, Box 8, Audiocassette 18_191)
  - Stamm, Morris, 1980; cuid9234 (Box 2, Cd ALBA A 18-192 A-B, Box 8, Audiocassette 18_191)
  - Steck, Robert, May 24, 1980; cuid9235 (Box 2, Cd ALBA A 18-193 A-B, Box 8, Audiocassette 18_193)
  - Steck, Robert, May 24, 1980; cuid9236 (Box 2, Cd ALBA A 18-194 A-B, Box 8, Audiocassette 18_194)
  - Susman, William (Bill), 1980; cuid9237 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_195)
  - Susman, William (Bill), 1980; cuid9238 (Box 8, Audiocassette 18_196)
  - Tenor, Leon, and Pat, 1980; cuid9239 (Box 2, Cd ALBA A 18-197, Box 8, Audiocassette 18_197)
  - Tisa, John and May, 1980; cuid243 (Box 2, Cd ALBA A 18-198, Box 8, Audiocassette 18_198)